Daniel Yankelovich Papers
© 2002 University of Connecticut
- Series I: Writings,undated, 1947-1992
  - Subseries B: Books,undated, 1947-1991
    - Starting With the People, with Sidney Harman, 1988
      - A New Political Framework (working title) with Les Aspin, Sidney Harman and John Immerwahr
        - Typescript draft, chapter 12, "'More for More'in Practice", 1985 Nov-Dec (Box 27:605)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 12, "A Flawed Framework?", 1986 Nov 25 (Box 27:606)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 13, "The Fingers of the Visible Hand", 1986 Nov 25 (Box 27:607)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 13, "A New Workplace", 1986 Nov 26 (Box 27:608)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 14, "The Commitment Gap", 1986 nov 26 (Box 28:609)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 15, "From 'Less-for-Less' to 'More-for-More'", 1986 Dec 2 (Box 28:610)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 16, "'More-for-More' in Practice", 1986 Dec 2 (Box 28:611)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 17, "A New Role for Unions", 1986 Dec 2 (Box 28:612)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 18, "The Visible Hand", 1986 Dec 2 (Box 28:613)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 34, "Policies of Peaceful Contention"
          - Draft, edited,1985 Jul 20 (Box 28:614)
          - Draft, edited,1985 Jul 24 (Box 28:615)
          - Draft,1985 Jul 30 (Box 28:616)
        - Typescript draft, new chapters 34 and 35, 1985 Aug (Box 28:617)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 34, "The Gap Between the Experts and the Public", 1985 Sep (Box 28:618)
        - Typescript draft, Part III, "Replaceing Nuclear Diplomacy"
          - Chapter 4, "The Boundaries of Political Acceptability",1986 (Box 28:619)
          - Chapter 7, "Strategy," edited,1986 (Box 28:620)
        - Miscellaneous draft segments, [1986] (Box 28:621)
        - Mailing list, 1986 (Box 28:622)
      - Starting with the Public (working title)/Starting with the People, with Sidney Harman
        - Notes
          - General,undated (Box 28:623)
          - Part I, "Replacing Nuclear Diplomacy",1986-1987 (Box 28:624)
          - Part I. chapters 8 and 9,1986-1987 (Box 28:625)
        - Book summary,1987 Apr 6 (Box 28:626)
        - "Outtakes",1987 (Box 28:627)
        - Typescript draft, Part II, Acknowledgments,1986 Jan (Box 28:628)
        - Typescript draft, Preface,1987 Jun (Box 28:629)
        - Typescript draft, Foreword, edited,1988 Jan (Box 28:630)
        - Typescript draft, Foreword by Cyrus Vance,undated (Box 28:631)
        - Memorandum concerning table of contents,1987 Mar (Box 28:632)
        - Typescript, draft, Introduction
          - "Why Start with The Public?",1986 Nov (Box 28:633)
          - "Creating Consensus" - outline of argument,1987 Oct 19 (Box 28:634)
          - "Creating Consensus",1987 Oct 22 (Box 28:635)
          - "Creating Consensus",1987 Oct 27 (Box 28:636)
          - "Starting with the Public",1987 Oct 29 (Box 28:637)
          - "Starting with the People", edited by the publisher,1987 Nov 2 (Box 28:638)
          - "Introduction": galley,1988 Mar (Box 28:639)
          - "Introduction": galley, edited by D. Yankelovich,1988 Mar (Box 28:640)
        - Typescript draft, Introduction, "Reframing the Problem",1987 Jun (Box 28:641)
        - Typescript draft, Introduction, "Value Driven Judgment",1988 Jan (Box 28:642)
        - "Toward an Industrial Consensus",1987 Jul (Box 28:643)
        - Typescript draft, chapter B1, "An End to Floundering?",1987 Apr (Box 28:644)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 1, "An End to Floundering?",1987 May (Box 29:645)
        - Typescript draft, chapter B2, "Caught Off Guard",1987 Apr (Box 29:646)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 2, ""From Effortless Superiority to Second Place",1987 May (Box 29:647)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 3, "The Loss of America's Competitive Advantage",1987 Jan (Box 29:648)
          - Draft,1987 Feb (Box 29:649)
        - Typescript draft, chapter B3, "The Underlying Cause - A Flawed Framework",1987 Apr (Box 29:650)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 3, "The Underlying Cause - A Flawed Framework",1987 May (Box 29:651)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 4, "A Flawed Framework (Boeskyism and Other Diversions)",1987 Jan (Box 29:652)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 4, "Conditions for Consensus",1987 Apr (Box 29:653)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 5/6, "More for More in Principle",1987 Apr (Box 29:654)
        - Typescript draft, chapter B5, "How the Japanese Won",1987 Apr (Box 29:655)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 5, "More for More in Principle",1987 May (Box 29:656)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 6, "How the Japanese Won",1987 May (Box 29:657)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 7, "Doing a Better Job at Work",1987 Apr (Box 29:658)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 7, "From Less-for-Less to More-for-More" ,1987 May (Box 29:659)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 8, "Doing a Better Job at Management",1987 Apr (Box 29:660)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 10, "More for More in Practice",1987 Apr (Box 29:661)
        - Typescript draft, Part II, "More for More",1987 May (Box 29:662-665)
        - Typescript draft, chapter B13, "What Went Wrong?",1987 Jul (Box 29:666)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 11, "Doing a Better Job in Our Institutions",1987 Apr (Box 29:667)
        - Typescript draft, chapter 14, "A Plan for Mobilizing Discretionary Effort",[1987] (Box 29:668)
        - Appendix A,1987 May (Box 29:669)
        - Chart titles and materials,1987 (Box 29:670)
        - Uncorrected proof,1988 (Box 29:671)
        - Uncorrected proof (copy 2),1988 (Box 29:672)
        - Author biography: S. Harman,1987 (Box 30:673)
        - Author biography: D. Yankelovich,1987 (Box 30:674)
        - BENS book party,1988 Jun 22 (Box 30:675)
        - Book publishing: notes,[1988] (Box 30:676)
        - Reviewer comments,1988 Apr-Jun (Box 30:677)
        - Comments from Forsberg: audio tapes,1987 Nov 15 (Box 30:678)
        - Finances,1987-1989 (Box 30:679)
        - Galley lists,1985-1988 (Box 30:680)
        - Interviews,1988 (Box 30:681)
        - Interview notes,1988 (Box 30:682)
        - Itineraries and schedules,1988 (Box 30:683)
        - Thank you letters,1988 Jun-Nov (Box 30:684)
        - Permission for quotes,1987-1988 (Box 30:685)
        - Press folders,1987-1988 (Box 30:686-687)
        - Reviews,1988 (Box 30:688)
        - Television summaries,1988 (Box 30:689)
    - 3 Epochs, [1955-1965]
      - Clippings, undated (Box 30:690)
      - Notes, undated (Box 30:691)
      - Notecards, undated (Box 30:692-693)
      - Typescript sections and notes, edited, undated (Box 30:694)
  - Subseries C: Other Writings,1977-1984
    - "The Failure of Consensus on Energy," Uncertain Power: The Struggle for a National Energy Policy, 1983 (Box 30:695)
    - "The Impact of Scarcities: The United States, Sweden, and the Federal Republic of Germany", 1977 Feb 23 (Box 30:696)
    - "Managing for Motivation in a High Discretion Workplace," with J. Immerwahr: abstract, 1983 (Box 30:697)
    - "Managing for Motivation in a High Discretion Workplace," with J. Immerwahr: remarks, 1983 (Box 31:698)
    - "When Reagonomics Fail, Then What?" The Reagan Presidency and the Governing of America, 1984 (Box 31:699)
  - Subseries D: Presentations,1959-1991
    - The 1997 Frank W.Abrams Lecture Series, Public Judgment,1987 (Box 30)
    - (SEE ALSO: pages 6-9, boxes 1-3)
    - AFL/CIO Committee on the Evolution of Work,1987 Nov 17 (Box 31:700-702)
    - American College of Psychiatrists 1991 Annual Meeting,1991 Feb 6-10 (Box 31:703-704)
    - BENS Campaign '92 Kickoff,1992 Feb 19 (Box 31:705)
    - "Coming to Public Judgment," Center for Communications Breakfast,1991 May 22 (Box 31:706-707)
    - "Competitiveness: How to Achieve a National Consensus," Minnesota Meeting,1987 May 14 (Box 31:708)
    - "Competitiveness: The Human Dimension Bring the Public to the Table," Business-Higher Education Forum,1990 Jan 25-27 (Box 31:709)
    - "Diversity and Core Values," SCAN Conference,1990 Dec (Box 31:710)
    - "How to Improve the US-Japan Relationship," Shimoda Conference,1990 Nov 15-17 (Box 31:711-712)
    - "Intermarriage in the America of the 1990's," The 1990 Conference on Jewish Intermarriage, Conversion, and Outreach,1990 Dec 5 (Box 31:713)
    - "Psychology and Church Problems," Senior Fellowship Talk,1959 Apr 26 (Box 31:714)
    - "Setting the Agenda," New School Lecture,1985 Feb 28 (Box 31:715)
    - SIT Investment Associates, Inc. Client Workshop,1988 Feb 11-14 (Box 31:716)
    - World Futures Society, "Business and the Future" Conference,1991 Sep 11-13 (Box 31:717)
- Series II: Projects,1949-1994
  - Subseries A: Harvard Business Review Projects,1949-1994
    - Class of 1949 Survey
      - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 32:718-719)
      - Official papers, 1993-1994 (Box 32:720)
      - Steering committee meetings, 1993-1994 (Box 32:721)
      - Finances, 1993-1994 (Box 32:722)
      - Notes: general, [1993-1994] (Box 32:723)
      - Letters to participants, 1993-1994 (Box 32:724)
      - Interview guide
        - Notes, [1993-1994] (Box 32:725)
        - Draft 1, 1993 Oct 13 (Box 32:726)
        - Draft 2, edited, 1993 Oct 23 (Box 32:727)
        - Final draft, edited, [1993-1994] (Box 32:728)
      - Faxed interviews, 1993 (Box 32:729-731)
      - Interview tabulations, 1993 (Box 32:732)
      - Interview quotes, 1993 (Box 32:733-734)
      - Class of '49 reunion questionnaire: development material, 1993 (Box 32:735)
      - Class of '49 reunion questionnaire, [1993] (Box 32:736)
      - Class of '49 reunion questionnaire tabulations, 1994 May (Box 32:737)
      - Survey results: notes, [1993-1994] (Box 32:738)
      - Yankelovich, D. and R. Tedlow, "What the Class of '49 Can Teach Us About Success"
        - Notes, 1994 (Box 32:739)
        - Tedlow, R.: drafts, 1993 Dec - 1994 Jan (Box 32:740)
        - Draft 2A, 1994 Jan 18 (Box 32:741)
        - Draft 2A, edited, 1994 Jan 18 (Box 32:742)
        - Draft 2C, edited, 1994 Jan 17 (Box 32:743)
        - Draft 2D, 1994 Jan 20 (Box 32:744)
        - Draft 3, edited, 1994 Jan 26 (Box 32:745)
        - Draft 4, edited, 1994 Feb 1 (Box 32:746)
        - Draft 4, 1994 Feb 2 (Box 32:747)
        - Draft 4, 1994 Feb 7 (Box 32:748)
        - Draft 4, changes, 1994 Feb 10 (Box 33:749)
        - Draft 5, 1994 Feb 10 (Box 33:750)
        - Final draft, 1994 May (Box 33:751)
        - Final draft (copy 2), 1994 May (Box 33:752)
        - Charts, [1994] (Box 33:753)
      - Typescript draft, "The Class of '49: A Self Portrait" - executive summary, 1994 Apr 22 (Box 33:754)
      - Typescript draft, "Harvard Business School Class of 1949: A Self Portrait" - executive summary, edited, 1994 May (Box 33:755)
      - Typescript final draft, "A Survey of the Harvard Business School Class of 1949" - Part I, executive summary, 1994 Jun (Box 33:756)
      - Typescript final draft, "A Survey of the Harvard Business School Class of 1949" - Part I, executive summary (copy 2), 1994 Jun (Box 33:757-758)
      - Typescript draft, "Harvard Business School Class of 1949 Survey Report", edited, 1994 Jun (Box 33:759-761)
      - Typescript draft, "Part II - The Research Report", [1994] (Box 33:762-764)
      - Typescript draft, "Part II - The Research Report" (copy 2), [1994] (Box 33:765-767)
      - Class of 1949 Reunion Presentation, 1994 Jun 3
        - Notes and arrangements, 1994 May (Box 34:768)
        - Presentation charts, 1994 Jun (Box 34:769)
        - Presentation charts: transparencies, 1994 Jun (Box 34:770)
        - Back-up quotes, 1994 Jun (Box 34:771)
      - Class of 1949 45th reunion profiles
        - A - Z, 1994 (Box 34:772-778)
      - Related articles, undated, 1949-1993 (Box 34:779)
    - Readership Survey
      - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 34:780)
      - Meeting notes, 1992 oct 23 (Box 34:781)
      - Letter to participants, [1992] (Box 34:782)
      - Interview forms, 1993 (Box 34:783)
      - Worksheets for telephone interviews - draft, 1993 Jun 16 (Box 34:784)
      - Interview guides, 1993 (Box 34:785)
      - Interview responses, [1993] (Box 34:786-787)
      - Response tabulations, 1993 (Box 34:788)
      - "Discards", [1993] (Box 34:789)
      - Typescript draft, presentation, edited, 1993 Nov 29 (Box 34:790-792)
      - Phase 1 findings: table of contents, [1993] (Box 35:793)
      - Invoice, 1993 May (Box 35:794)
      - Erdos and Morgan/MPG Subscriber Survey, 1993 (Box 35:795)
      - Harvard Business Review supplements, 1993 (Box 35:796)
      - Related articles, undated, 1992-1994 (Box 35:797)
  - Subseries B: Nuclear Policy Projects,undated, 1969-1990
    - Correspondence, 1982-1988 (Box 35:798-806)
    - Memoranda, undated, 1984-1987 (Box 35:807-810)
    - Voter Options on Nuclear Arms Policy - A Briefing Book for the 1984 Elections, 1984
      - "Towards Public Judgment on the Nuclear Defense Issue": project proposal,1983 Oct (Box 35:811)
      - Brown University meeting: notes,1983 Dec 5 (Box 35:812)
      - Bob Lifton meeting: notes,1984 Feb 19 (Box 35:813)
      - Brown University nuclear workshop,1984 Apr 19-20 (Box 35:814)
      - Voter Options workshop,1984 May 10 (Box 35:815)
      - Institute for East-West Security Studies nuclear workshop,1984 May 22 (Box 35:816)
      - Focus group interviews,1984 Jan-Feb (Box 35:817)
      - Nuclear defense issue questionnaire - draft 1,1984 Apr (Box 35:818)
      - Nuclear defense issue: secondary source data,1984 May (Box 35:819)
      - Public Agenda Foundation nuclear arms and national security questionnaire,[1984] (Box 35:820)
      - Public Agenda Foundation nuclear arms and national security survey statistics,198 (Box 36:821-822)
      - Preliminary tables from nuclear survey,1984 Jun (Box 36:823)
      - Preliminary tables from nuclear survey (copy 2),1984 Jun (Box 36:824-825)
      - Survey results - six areas of conflict concerning the Soviet threat and nuclear weapons, [1984]
        - Areas 1-6, [1984] (Box 35:826-831)
      - Survey results: miscellaneous,[1984] (Box 36:832)
      - Schmookler, Andrew, expert assumptions chapter draft,1984 (Box 36:833)
      - Materials excluded from consensus section,[1984] (Box 36:834)
      - Tables: chapter 1,[1984] (Box 36:835)
      - Voter Options on Nuclear Arms Policy - A Briefing Book for the 1984 Election,1984 (Box 36:836)
      - Voter Options on Nuclear Arms Policy - A Briefing Book for the 1984 Election (copy 2),1984 (Box 36:837)
      - Voter Options on Nuclear Arms Policy - A Briefing Book for the 1984 Election - Technical Appendix,1984 (Box 36:838)
      - Book promotion for Voter Options,1984 (Box 36:839)
    - The Public, The Soviets, and Nuclear Arms
      - Brown University meeting, 1984 Dec 17 (Box 36:840)
      - Brown University/Public Agenda Foundation meeting, 1985 Mar 5 (Box 36:841)
      - Brown University/Public Agenda Foundation meeting, 1985 Nov 15 (Box 37:842)
      - Center for Foreign Policy Development research conference, 1986 Mar 11 (Box 37:843)
      - Brown University/Public Agenda Foundation meetings, 1986 Apr, Oct (Box 37:844-845)
      - Nuclear "vision" discussion, 1986 Nov 12 (Box 37:846)
      - Brown University/Public Agenda Foundation project executive committee meeting, 1986 Dec 1 (Box 37:847)
      - Brown University/Public Agenda Foundation meeting, 1986 Dec 22 (Box 37:848)
      - Brown University/Public Agenda Foundation executive committee meeting, 1987 Jan 28 (Box 37:849)
      - Project proposal
        - Notes, 1985 (Box 37:850)
        - Abstract, edited, 1985 (Box 37:851)
        - "Rationale" section-draft 4, 1985 Jan 31 (Box 37:852)
        - Overview draft, 1985 Feb 23 (Box 37:853)
        - Overview draft, [1985] (Box 37:854)
        - Typescript draft, introduction, 1985 (Box 37:855)
        - Typescript draft, introduction, edited, 1985 (Box 37:856)
        - "The Public and the Nation's Nuclear Arms POlicy", edited, 1985 Jun (Box 37:857-858)
      - John D. and Catherine T. McArthur Foundation, 1984 (Box 37:859)
      - American Psychiatric Association, 1983 May-Sep (Box 37:860)
      - National Council, 1986 (Box 37:861)
      - Funds for nuclear project, 1986-1988 (Box 37:862)
      - Moscow meetings: summary, 1986 Jun (Box 37:863)
      - Nuclear focus groups, 1985 (Box 37:864)
      - Summary of focus group res, 1987 (Box 37:865)
      - Community leaders' workshops, 1985-1986 (Box 37:866)
      - Concept papers, 1986 (Box 37:867)
      - Project notebook, 1986 (Box 37:868-870)
      - Project notebook, 1986 (Box 38:871-872)
      - Questionnaire #2 - post-test, weighted results, 1988 Feb (Box 38:873)
      - "Public Attitudes Toward the Nuclear Issue: A Segmentation Analysis", [1986] (Box 38:874)
      - Internal reports
        - A Perspective From Community Leaders - internal report, 1986 Sep (Box 38:875)
        - The View of Community Leaders - internal report (2 copies), 1986 Sep (Box 38:876)
      - Working papers
        - "Choices for the Public on Nuclear Arms and the Soviets" - draft, 1986 Feb (Box 38:877)
        - "Choices for the Public on Nuclear Arms and the Soviets" - draft, 1986 May (Box 38:878)
        - "Discussion of Public Choices for U.S. Policy Toward the Soviets and the Risk of Nuclear War", 1986 Jul (Box 38:879)
        - "The Public, the Soviets, and Nuclear Arms, an Experiment in Public Judgment" with John Immerwahr, 1989 Jul (Box 38:880)
        - "The Public, the Soviets, and Nuclear Arms, an Experiment in Public Judgment" (copy 2), 1989 Jun (Box 38:881)
      - Project content paper prologue - draft, 1987 May (Box 38:882)
      - Project content paper - draft, 1987 May (Box 38:883)
      - Four Futures pamphlet, 1987 (Box 38:884)
      - DPA nuclear book - draft, edited, 1987 apr (Box 38:885)
      - ABC News Nightline: discussion material, 1987 Sep 3 (Box 38:886)
      - Statement of D. Yankelovich before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1988 Mar 16 (Box 38:887)
      - "An End to the Cold War?" - op-ed draft, 1988 May (Box 38:888)
      - Public Summit '88: information packet, 1988 (Box 38:889)
      - Public Summit '88: ballot results, 1988 (Box 38:890)
      - "A Mandate for the Future" - booklet, 1988 (Box 38:891)
      - U.S.-Soviet Relations in the Year 2010: Americans Look to the Future" - draft, [1988] (Box 38:892-893)
      - U.S.-Soviet Relations in the Year 2010: Americans Look to the Future, 1988 (Box 39:894-895)
      - U.S.-Soviet Relations in the Year 2010: Americans Look to the Future (copy 2), 1988 (Box 39:896-897)
      - U.S.-Soviet Relations in the Year 2010: Americans Look to the Future - Technical Appendix, 1988 (Box 39:898-899)
      - Project Briefing Book, 1988 (Box 39:900-902)
      - Publications list and order form, [1988] (Box 39:903)
    - Dartmouth Conferences
      - (SEE ALSO: page 122, box 100)
      - Kettering Foundation, 1984-1990 (Box 39:904)
      - Dartmouth XIV, 1984 May 14-17
        - Correspondence, 1983 Jul - 1984 Apr (Box 39:905)
        - Work group on political and economic relations: meeting, 1984 Mar 7 (Box 39:906)
        - Preparatory meeting, 1984 Apr 12-13 (Box 39:907)
        - Information packet, 1984 May (Box 39:908)
        - Background readings, 1984 (Box 39:909-911)
        - Notes, 1984 (Box 39:912)
        - Stewart, Philip D., "Dartmouth Conference XIV - A Soviet American Dialogue" - draft, 1984 Jul (Box 40:913)
        - Stewart, Philip D.,, "Dartmouth Conference XIV - A Soviet American Dialogue", 1984 (Box 40:914)
      - Dartmouth XV, 1986 May 13-17
        - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 40:915)
        - Preparatory meeting, 1986 Apr 16 (Box 40:916)
        - List of participants, 1986 May (Box 40:917)
        - Yankelovich presentation: transcript draft, 1984 May 16 (Box 40:918)
        - Notes, 1986 (Box 40:919)
        - Notebooks, 1986 (Box 40:920)
        - Debriefing notes, 1986 May (Box 40:921)
        - Stenographic Report, 1986 Sep (Box 40:922)
        - Miscellaneous, 1984-1986 (Box 40:923)
      - Dartmouth XVI, 1988 Apr 24-May 7
        - Conference information, 1987-1988 (Box 40:924)
        - Yankelovich, D., "Prospects for a New Era in U.S.-Soviet Relations" - presentation, 1988 Apr
          - Chart presentation and notes, 1988 Apr 29 (Box 40:925)
          - Transparencies, 1988 Apr 29 (Box 40:926)
          - Back up notes, 1988 (Box 40:927)
        - Notes, 1988 (Box 40:928)
        - Kettering Foundation, Dartmouth Conference XVI: A U.S.-Soviet Program in Supplemental Diplomacy, 1988 (Box 40:929)
        - National Issues Forum Soviet Dialogue Conference, 1988 Apr 30-May 4 (Box 40:930)
      - Dartmouth Conference Arms Control Task Force - summary report, 1984 Mar 10-12 (Box 40:931)
      - Dartmouth Conference Arms Control Task Force - summary report, 1985 Nov 28-30 (Box 40:932)
      - Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Political Relations
        - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 40:933-934)
        - Correspondence, 1986 Jan 21 (Box 40:935)
        - List of participants, 1986 (Box 40:936)
          - Notes,1986 (Box 40:937)
          - Miscellaneous,1986 (Box 40:938)
        - Session 2, 1986 Dec 5-6
          - Remarks by H. H. Saunders,1986 Dec 6 (Box 40:939)
          - Executive Summary,1986 Dec 5-6 (Box 40:940)
          - Excerpts,1986 Dec 5-6 (Box 40:941)
          - Notes,1986 Dec 6 (Box 40:942)
        - Session 4: information, 1988 Feb 18-20 (Box 41:943)
          - Meeting: report, 1989 Jan 19-21
      - Dartmouth Conference Task Force on Prevention and Settlement of International Conflicts: summary report, 1983 Nov 29-Dec 1 (Box 41:945)
      - Dartmouth Conference Regional Conflict Task Force, 1986 Nov 11-13 (Box 41:946)
      - Dartmouth Conference Task Force on South Africa: report, 1985 Oct 1-2 (Box 41:947)
      - Chibisenkov, V. S.,, "The Dartmouth Conference", 1983 (Box 41:948)
      - Stewart, Philip D.,, "Informal Diplomacy: The Dartmouth Conference Experience", 1985 Mar (Box 41:949)
      - Stewart, Philip D. and Margaret G. Hermann, "Soviet 'New Thinking' about Security: Implications for Deterrence", 1987 Oct 21 (Box 41:950)
      - General notes on Dartmouth Conference, undated (Box 41:951)
    - Related Nuclear Material
      - Notes
        - General notes, 1985-1986 (Box 41:952-955)
        - Defense community thinking, undated (Box 41:956)
        - Notes from key papers, undated (Box 41:957)
        - "Nuclear Choices": notebook, 1984 (Box 41:958)
      - Books, journal issues and reports
        - Adams, Gordon and Stephen Cain, The Legacy of the Military Build-up: Choices for the 1990's, 1988 (Box 41:959)
        - AEI Foreign POlicy and Defense Review
          - Volume 4, nos. 5, 6,1984 (Box 41:960)
          - Volume 5, no. 2, 1985 (Box 41:961)
        - The Americas in 1989 - Consensus for Action, A Report of the Inter-American Dialogue, 1989 (Box 41:962)
        - The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science
          - Volume 469 "Nuclear Armament and Disarmament", 1983 Sep (Box 41:963)
          - Volume 481 "Soviet Foreign POlicy in an Uncertain World", 1985 Sep (Box 41:964)
        - Arms Control Today
          - Volume 13, nos. 4, 5, 8, 9, 11, 1984 (Box 41:965)
          - Volume 14, nos. 9, 10, 1984 (Box 42:966)
          - Volume 16, no. 1, and Herbert Scoville, Jr. Memorial Issue, 1985-1986 (Box 42:967)
        - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, Proliferation, Politics, and the IAEA: The Issue of Nuclear Safeguards, 1985 (Box 42:968)
        - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, Nuclear Power and National and International Security, 1984 (Box 42:969)
        - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, Managing East-West Conflict, 1984 (Box 42:970)
        - Bialer, Seweryn, The USSR After Brezhnev, 1983 (Box 42:971)
        - Bialer, Seweryn, L. Hamilton, J. Hough and J. Steinbruner, U.S.-Soviet Relations: Perspectives for the Future, 1984 (Box 42:972)